# MANOJ SHAKAR

PRODUCT DESIGNER



+91 999 444 8205



manojshakar.com@gmail.com



www.manojshakar.com

## PROFILE

Experienced User Experience Designer with a demonstrated history of working in the various industries & clients all over the world who is responsible for creating usable and delightful online experiences. I have a skill set of design strategy, user research, information architecture and content strategy, user interface design, Iconography, illustration and usability testing. I also have a better knowledge of HTML, CSS, Javascript.

# EMPLOYMENT

### JULY 2018 - PRESENT

### **Product Designer**

#### Freshworks

A fast growing SAAS company giving me lot of exposure to product design, user research, card sorting, rapid prototyping etc. The bunch of super smart people and the state of art office gives me more creative thoughts and works.

## OCT 2016 - JUNE 2018

### **UX Designer**

#### Trimble Information Technology

A large scale corporate giving me opportunity to work with large amount of data that deals with heavy civil construction machines

## JUNE 2016 - AUG 2016

### **UI** Designer

### ZoomRx

A pharma market research startup gave me the lesson of detailing in designing and perfection of the work your deliver

#### JAN 2016 - MAY 2016

## **UI Designer / Developer**

#### Triton IT solutions.

A young surrounding gave me positive vibes to work with fresh bloods and learned the ethics and sense in scripting languages

#### APRIL 2015 - DEC 2015

## **Graphic & Web Designer**

#### Sri Hema Infotech

A startup web designing company in perambur, chennnai. This firm gave me the gateway to the feild of deisgning.

A place where i learned knowledge about deisgning and developing web and mobile products.

# EDUCATION

### B.E - CSE

2010 - 2014

#### Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham, Coimbatore

Completed my BE-CSE in Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham Coimbatorewith **70.39%** 

## Senior Secondary School (XII STD)

2008 - 2010

S.R.V. Matric Higher Secondary School, Trichy

Completed my Senior secondary schooling from S.R.V.

Matric Higher Secondary School with 80.33%

## Secondary school (X STD)

2000 - 2008

Y.W.C.A Matric Secondary School, Trichy

Completed my Secondary schooling from Y.W.C.A Matric

Higher Secondary School with 80.44%

# SKILLS

#### DESIGN

UX Research

**User Studies** 

**Usability Evaluation** 

Information Architecture

User Experience Design

Wireframing

Prototyping

Rapid Prototyping

User Persona

Service design

**Motion Graphics** 

Interface design

Iconography

Illustration

Digital Painting

Branding

### TOOLS

Sketch

Adobe XD

Principle

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe After Effects

Adobe Premiere Pro

## Languages

HTML5

CSS3

Javascript

С

C++

## INTEREST

## **Photography**

More Passionate about storytelling via photography. Love to explore the world via my Canon and iPhone.

## **Motorhead**

The love for cars and bikes started in my chilldhood.

Other than designing, You can find me riding car and bikes and Customizing them in my friends garage.

### **Cricket**

The love for cricket started during my School days, only sport you can find me actively involved.







